A Guide to the Confederate Miscellany, 1861-1865
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Confederate Miscellany, 1861-1865
The Library of Virginia
22812
15 leaves, negative photostats
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Lent for copying, 1948, by the Confederate Museum, Richmond, Virginia.
Scope and Content
Miscellaneous items, 1861-1865, containing correspondence, 1861-1863, consisting of letters discussing J. Gottlieb's enlistment in the Confederate army, Green Berry Pockress's (d. 1862) service in the 12th Alabama Infantry and his death in battle, and Major Hermann Hirsch's complaint against a brigade quartermaster; orders, 1861, issued by Colonel William M. Levy, 2nd Louisiana Infantry, concerning L. Flourney's appointment as adjutant, drills, and respect for civilian property; circulars, 1861 and 1865, concerning transportation and ordnance; receipt for gold turned over to the United States; and a broadside containing Rabbi Maximilian J. Michelbacher's "The Prayer of the Confederate Soldier."
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Location of Originals
Museum of the Confederacy, Richmond, Virginia.
Contents List
- Letter, 12 June 1861, from J. Gottlieb of Mississippi to S. Abeles of Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, stating that Gottlieb has joined the Confederate army and wishing Abeles well.
- Orders no. 1, 6 September 1861, issued by Colonel William M. Levy of the 2nd Louisiana Regiment appointing L. Flourney adjutant.
- Orders no. 2, 7 September 1861, issued by Colonel Levy concerning drills.
- Orders no. 3, 7 September 1861, issued by Colonel Levy warning soldiers not to damage civilian property.
- Circular, 1 December 1861, from A. C. Moyers, quartermaster-general, concerning transportation.
- Letter, 12 May 1862, from Green Berry Pockress (d. 1862) of the 12 Alabama Regiment to Joseph Millhiser informing him how Pockress is doing.
- Letter, 8 June 1862, from A. T. Preston of the 12th Alabama to Charles Millhiser in Richmond, Virginia, concerning the battle of Seven Pines and the death of Pockress.
- Letter, 12 June 1863, from Major Hermann Hirsch, quartermaster's office, Savannah, Georgia, to Major B. F. McKinne, Chief Quartermaster, District of Georgia, Savannah, Georgia, complaining about a brigade quartermaster.
- Circular, 5 January 1865, from Captain Jaquelin Smut at headquarters, Pocotaligo, South Carolina, to Lieutenant O. Cohen, acting ordnance officer, Coosawhatchie, South Carolina, asking how much ordnance Cohen has requested for his unit.
- Receipt, 5 May 1865, from Major R. R. Wood to Major R. I. Moses for $3000 in gold turned over to the United States.
- Broadside, no date, of "The Prayer of the C.S. Soldiers" by Rabbi Maximilian J. Michelbacher of Richmond, Virginia, being a copy forwarded by Michelbacher to Max Myers.